as we go live I kind of need to cough
welcome to our live board meeting which
we don't quite know if it's a board
meeting today I can give an update I
won't we talked about last week tomorrow
is our first solution raising its on
education and it will take place here at
9:00 a.m. Pacific Standard Time we'll be
discussing how we can have an inclusive
education system or an accessible an
accessible education system for everyone
that should be fun because it's our
first time doing it and we'll see how it
goes 15 minutes to discuss the problem
and how it currently works a few minutes
to discuss the future and how it could
work and then half an hour to come up
with a potential solution that is doable
with 10,000 people and $100,000 and then
next week or two weeks after that
because I'm going to be in Ritchie's
project at 2 p.m. the next week he
okayed that he said that that works for
him so it should be good a different
time slot on the 29th of February our
bonus day a leap year and then today we
don't we could talk about the Facebook
group the game be when we all joined the
technology one you know I think that
might be an interesting discussion all
right
the other option is to just talk about
trust or Dewey more men a project of
that but we were kind of shaky on that
at the end the last one so was it it
wasn't fully decided how I haven't
actually had that much of a chance to
look at that Facebook group I don't know
are there they're looking at existing
tools right more so than creating them
from seemed like it but it also seems
quite new and the vibe I got is they're
trying to solve a lot of the same
problems as we are so there's proyects
seems like a really good sort of
collection to people and just that the
whole goal is the same as the gold I got
a second is a spork meeting it seems
like there could be some really good
overlap yeah yeah and I was looking at
us wondering yeah we're not in
competitive space so it takes me a
little while to get used to
meeting though yes so I mean this may be
another point where we have to like you
know because they're they're moving on
soon to be as far as I could tell
unaware of anything that we've done so
far or so yeah I did I guess the only
thing I'm trying to think is make sure
that I'm kind of prepared to change
direction as necessary but also there's
a good chance that what they're doing
won't actually have the same overlap and
it may not change anything we do yeah I
did see the I think it was the first
group of groups which seemed to give the
same sort of vibe as the meta project as
like the general goal yeah but I think
you're you're right Pentti in that I
think that actually might end up being
like almost two sides of the same coin
where they seem to be more focused on a
you know existing tech and what can we
use and well what would watch UAVs and
you talk about and then as far as I can
tell we're trying to solve like the
actual project a project how can we
share you know what does cooperation
look like in a world where we have to
get used to cooperate and not competing
and and that whole thing so I mean I'm
sure we'll end up stepping on you know
various toes if as we try to figure out
who goes where and who's doing what but
I'm glad you found that incentive pose
yeah I it's funny I can Facebook
searches so horrible I can't even find
it now I mean I can you'll find the link
that I put out there but I just thought
I'd go to my groups tab and it'd be
there but apparently yeah it seems to
take a while it took game be a while to
show up in like groups to have one
Facebook it's also a nerd pin it
conversations which is it's funny
because it's like chunking down what
gave the game be Facebook group is is
like conversations it's just
conversation it's just like video
conversations posted I really if y'all
saw the original post before they it's
an
intentional break down into five
different sites or something so the main
one is the game B menu actually I can't
remember the name of it now that has a
link to all the other I game be homepage
so if you haven't seen that you might
just go and look and see if there's any
other groups you want to participate in
and the shortcuts there we go yeah
conversations can be online tools the
wiki which we're also both part of Cuba
to point out which I don't know how
maybe that is like I feel like or maybe
justice Bambi or also a few of us a part
of that communities and hango so I'm not
part of communities or hangout I don't
know what hangouts supposed to be a
space for game view members to chat
about their hobbies and interests no
politics and then the communities is
like the physical space which i think is
um yeah someone who's gotten in touch
with both Bentley and I about their
project I don't know he's in the game be
space might be the person watcher
analysis as I add the same yeah so I've
been reading through his project say
that's one of the fun things well beer
in this space is getting to read I feel
like how directors gets scripts given to
them to look through it's like next
world-changing project next
world-changing project what do you think
of this and it's fun I enjoy it I enjoy
looking through other people so it's
like a 45 pager but it's very similar to
ideas I've had and I'm sure both of you
have had as well it's not focusing on
creating a community and how to
extrapolate that anyway and yes you know
and I thought on the game be ho pages
there was also a group for doing in
person communities I don't know if you
saw that an area mention it but we might
make sure he's aware
that unless I missed it do you mean in
person like meeting up in real life and
having like this kind of complication
like living together in real life yeah
that is that evening communities okay
okay cuz it was people like Kali and who
are more focused on on that that aspect
and that's why I brought up site yeah
what is like that that's that like type
of project I destroyed all keys in game
be because he contacted me through
Facebook in a different way but looking
at his Facebook career like normally I
don't accept friend requests that are
from people I don't have multiple
friends in common with but looking at
his Facebook page I was like no you have
enough other stuff in common and you
look like a real person so I'm good yeah
and that my facebook group is now
populated with game be people that an
AOL which seem speaks
imploding at the moment it's like all my
communities have have crap going on at
the moment so it's interesting it's an
interesting kind of culture this time my
body seems tough tumultuous times to as
the moment um yeah I don't know like I
said I haven't actually looked at the
technologies game be part yet but it
looks promising like to me though like I
wanted a spreadsheet you we talked about
before like I want to know when I have a
problem what tools the best and how did
these features compared to these
features and then I want us to all get
to the same conclusion and none of these
are gonna cut it because you'll have to
interconnect and we need something
that's gonna like be brought from that
from the ground up which might not
happen but yes so far they have they've
posted like five different existing
online tools so high low COAG of tech I
don't think I was aware of any of these
high low we talked to the last week
right that was that the one okay and
that's all tech like help manage a
member community that they're looking at
now well I don't think that that's
specific
no that's just I mean it's just tools to
be useful in building our game be and
and a group of groups home but they
haven't said what they mean by group of
groups home so I think they're throwing
out different you know Kevin Jones
throwing out different ideas and Jim
saying well that's not what I was
thinking so to say that they have a
clear direction I think would be a
little bit premature okay but like the
start of having people there just like
thinking we need yeah yeah it's I'm not
even really exactly sure I was gonna
post on there but I haven't yet to say
okay so what features are we looking for
cuz I know what you and I what with us
well we've been discussing about kind of
what a group of groups needs you know to
be able to find your place and stuff
like that but I don't I don't know from
what they've said that that's really
what they're looking for I mean they
just may be looking at a chat tool
that's not that's open source that you
know right yeah
based on the name of it I would expect
it to be multiple things and so I think
that it should almost be like how you
know a big enterprise company deals with
something like this we're like hey
here's the ten things that we need like
the ten problems that we need to solve
probably each one with a different piece
of software we're going to look at
something like community just as you did
Bentley trying to figure out what
features do they need cool and then
creating a system around it like if
we're trying to solve this problem
here's the ten features that might have
here's for each of these five solution
sits here's you know the rough score
that we gave and why and then in the end
you end up with oh this has the highest
score seems like the best one and then
you can see it is it good enough or not
and to move forward or we just saying
there's not a good enough tool here
together with friends in the weekend and
one of them I was not I was like half
asleep we were talking but um he like we
got a Facebook page for idea idea Cafe
IO and he's looking to make a wordpress
site for it and he sent me what the one
that I just put in the chat which is
just a plug-in that's a forum plug-in
and I'm like I don't know if he
understood what I'm trying to create I
don't remember the conversation because
I remember him definitely coming to the
idea that the forum was the way but I
don't actually remember the conversation
but maybe you guys not during this
conversation
we could take a look at it and tell me
if you think it could could work for the
idea Cafe the like for the scheduling
tool I think the idea wants to have a
space that I'm like I feel like face a
Facebook group might be better though
and a forum for all the rules we've
discussed before but how to use
WordPress to facilitate idea cafe or
like that the scheduling piece of
conversations which is maybe
conversation with the conversation
people in the schedule and I'm doing
yeah I'm gonna do that clarifying post
in the so ability to list out you know
what oh what are we looking for like the
ability to list out groups but earlier
those top peoples match the two chatting
documents or a copy of collaborative
document editing yeah so I was gonna
post that the other day and got
distracted so yeah they'll get a little
clarity in there but yeah so it's
interesting we'll just see how much that
kind of overlaps with what we want to do
yeah dad I mean I don't think there's
any problem with overlap especially this
point in time when it's basically want
to do something run with it run with it
until it like comes up strongly against
something else and then pick which one's
the best I guess yeah we're both from
parallel until I did want to suggest a
conversation so Jubilee I don't know if
this would fit in or the idea cafes but
a couple times we've talked about kind
of documentation about game being and
stuff like that and specifically Jonelle
has brought up a concern about making
things too concrete and I don't feel
like I understand enough of that concern
but I haven't figured out how to phrase
how to have a conversation about that
I'm not even sure what terms to used I'd
have to go look it up I don't know if
that would that fit into the kind of a
game B topics I if we could craft it
into a question yeah
it would fit with the idea cafe but
don't understand Janelle's stance I like
I had the conversation with one of the
Omega groups I think it was the
Wednesday one we're talking about like
permeable membranes and how like they
one of the issues at the game be
Facebook group is that it's you're
either in or you're out right and so you
and in that way that it's concrete and
it but it like both doesn't have a
boundary and does have a boundary and I
would need to re-watch the end table to
explain it but like to me that like
Gabey needs to exist outside of one
thing at the same time it's very
confusing without it being concrete like
without kind of having a calendar of
what's going on and definitions and
which is kind of what the wiki is trying
to do and things are coming together and
kind of coalescing but I need it to be
concrete like it's like how we need the
tools and the tools to be not five
different people and game be working on
a very similar project that isn't like
none of them are gonna work because the
energy is dissipated and half the
projects are in genell's and half the
projects are on kira hazardous or
Kiley's and like it's having those
conversations and the idea is that it
having more organization breaks it and
I'm like I need organization like
there's something there but was there
the concern provided as to what they
want things to be concrete well it she
she phrased it I'm just not sure that I
could read reiterate it and it
effectively I didn't understand it
enough to reiterate but I understood it
I mean part of resilience is not having
and so the concerns I think is is
reducing resilience and creating dogma
but I think you can have structure I
think you can have suggestions without
having mandates I think you can have you
know documentation without dogma so but
I need to understand better what our
concerns are to make sure that we can
get what Jubilee and I would like
without encroaching into her concerns so
yeah I don't know how to phrase that
maybe we could just approach Joan Allen
and say it kind of
even take a couple for phrase day we
heard you say this we don't understand
it can we have a meeting to discuss it
and we discussion on resilience the wiki
being too concrete or the space or what
discussions data that I'm recalling were
before the wiki it's when people were
talking about or maybe it was actually
in the wiki video discussion no but at
some point we were talking as the
onboarding I think the last time I
remember her bringing up was on on the
onboarding and that's they actually
decided to not do onboarding based on
that concern and I think that that's
that's a bit binary I think I think
there's a way you can do an introduction
without building Dogma but I didn't
understand enough of what the concern
was to be able to actually write I mean
engage yeah I was like it's I would kind
of agree that like the initial intro
maybe shouldn't be too concrete and
dogmatic but then per project like if
somebody wants to make a really open
flowy nebulous thing because they feel
like that's what they should be they can
do that it sounds like everyone involved
so far with together tech is a fan of it
being concrete but like adjustable you
know so we started out saying here's
what that is oh people don't agree okay
what should this term be yeah okay all
right that's the new definition I don't
think that her discussion had anything
to do with projects just with game be
space in general so I don't even know
that her concern would be on a project
basis so for together tech but she
seemed but it since some of our together
tech ideas are talking about documenting
game be like that's our reason for the
participation in the wiki I'd like to
make sure I understand that concern
before we go too far yeah and I think
it's a ballad she seems to have put a
lot of thought into it yeah I think it
is important to note like from what I'm
seeing from what they together tech is
it's our best guess as to what game B
looks like put into practice I'd like to
start actually working on okay so how do
we collaborate on projects and how do we
do this and you need to be concrete cuz
we're actually trying to do things as
to Peary captaining and you know trying
to figure that out we're gonna be wrong
more than they are because we're being
concrete and that's something that we
have to be able to and she's very much
in that place like I mean she's also
working on stuff and doing it but it's
also a little bit along from the divine
I get like oh people will just find
their people and form things and that
nebula sness feel like lead there which
I both agree with and also as somebody
who finds it hard to find my people
until I found game B it's not a
guarantee can we put something a little
more concrete where like people aren't
just wishy-washy in this space like wait
how do I participate how do I like to be
able to have an option for onboarding
even if it's not mandatory to be like
hey if you want to find out more go here
right here are the things you can
participate in right away here the
things you need to be at this level
before you participate in or whatever
those like the more we can make it
accessible to people the better but I
think you do for the concrete thing is
somewhat the towel that can be named
camping once you've named it it's not
the towel or whatever that saying is
that it comes up all the time it's like
italic we named it's not the towel and
it's like yes but that's not really game
be like it's like both yes it's in the
future and no we are never going to
obtain it and there are real things we
can be doing to make that the best
possibility and bring people on board
and how do we work with people on board
and how do we do it with existing
technique rate new tech and for that not
to be concrete is going to hurt it worse
than how I might I might choose a
different word than concrete because
concrete does imply unchangeable yeah
well you just want something specific
Breitling down rocks cool it's really
that's really all we want we just what
it accessible and document it could
change and it can be say this is not you
know this is not an end-all beyond and
maybe that should be the first rule
right before rule Omega is we don't know
what we're doing it subjective eternally
under construction something like that
Chiz oh yeah the frustration I have felt
with not being able to get my idea down
on like a white paper and get it out
into the world has been definitely
dissipated over like when I see people's
white pages and I like can be like well
but this doesn't work and this works
this doesn't work like the idea of
together Tech and a big tech cooperative
that anyone can join is that as people
join it it shifts and changes completely
like you know once you have a business
plan it's it's outdated anyway and so
having something that is like a living
document whatever that means is evolving
and changing and it's kind of like
coming participate in it and say what it
what it is and that's that's not
concrete that is like way too nebulous
for people and yet I'm suing for hello
yes and finding the I don't think you
can hear us whisper when you're any
honest
I had technical difficulties and
apparently still have but I did try to
catch up with you guys and the life
YouTube video stream and so creating
like what we're doing here although
we're all game B players isn't game B
right like we're not even purport it's
like very parallel very we're trying to
recreate on me win but like if we fail
game B doesn't fail if game B fails we
don't fail right like it's like very
like we're creating an omni wind we're
using technology we're getting together
figuring out how how to get done in
the public eye while like just figure it
all that piece out the messy part all of
it so that everyone can see so that even
if we fail there's something that comes
out of it right like we might be hey
these three things seem to work those
two may have been what hunk that project
yeah cool we'll take those no everyone
can have them and then the next group to
try the same thing to the key and learn
from it yeah and maybe I'm thinking as I
thinking through maybe her goal is to
keep game be more nebulous
and then the individual projects can
come at Ghibli just said rise and fall
and regular evolution make sense and it
sounds like and I think your point
definitely was a strong one where
concrete is the varying ways people can
take that will definitely be a point of
like people I think the term I've used
in the past is violently agreeing with
each other where it sounds like you're
arguing is Xperia Lee yeah I violently
create people out the side yeah sure but
not quite like that um and I like being
I like the idea of having it organized
more so than concrete
like I want efficient organized without
it being hierarchical top-down like I
just got another lesson this week in one
of my favorite people has this like me
too thing happening and and I'm like
because he's the central figure of this
entire culture if he goes down the
culture goes down with him like
especially since it's based on
authenticity he wasn't being very
authentic and so it's like that is
fragile right if Jordan Hall has it has
a scandal a gym rut has a scandal if
something like that happens and then it
falls apart like that's not what game be
as game be is like in the hearts of
minds of a lot of people not just one
person and yet it is kind of falling
apart and falling together at the same
time it's like a weird
it is nebulous and but not to have it be
a concrete like a project could be a
concrete thing at one with one person's
vision right and like bringing people on
board but one thing failing isn't gonna
make all the other ones fail and owning
that like making it as resilient as
possible like together tech right like
how do we keep together tech strong
independent of the projects that its
facilitating right and independent of
game B and this and if it goes down or
stays up or and I mean the Facebook
group specifically which isn't game B
but I'm wondering how that nebulosity
can be also applied to actual projects
to specific projects like can I can
we see how game B in itself is this
nebulous thing and it meets that to some
degree because otherwise it might well
for about but for projects can they also
stay nebulous for some time
I'm just really generally wondering
about it right now
I I would say yes and so like you you
want to get more specific and you want
to get more documented but I think you
want to like those guys they have the
first statement or claim being we're
going to change fast and nothing we
written we've written so far as it
should be considered permanent then we
should probably fight that tendency for
as long as possible at some time at some
point if you're actually like creating
technology or something something's got
to solidify but but yeah so nebulous is
game be especially nowadays with these
the possibilities of taking all kind of
open source and then forking it and
creating your own branch of stuff and it
does feel like it's at least getting
more and more also into this kind of
sometimes a little bit nebulous what
this is actually doing you start doing
something and then people have different
ideas and I mean I think if game B is
the goal then each project is like oh I
think I know how to to get there and
then the challenge is of course that we
aren't all 100% in agreement with what
the goal is
so it's which is the fun you know it's
like having like I think tomorrow's a
solution raising and it's gonna be
interesting for that very reason it's
like even just the coming up with the
question who like I didn't like that
question I want to offer this question
I'm like we are the questions decide
about and the point isn't to like we're
not looking at education breaking it
down into all of its problems sitting
with it for hours and days and years and
like how do we fix it it's like
literally in an hour we're coming up
with a solution that's a potentially
viable solution and so making
if we ever made it isn't nebulous or but
neither is the hour-long conversation
right it's like what we're having we're
gonna see how that goes we're gonna see
what that process looks like and I'm
hoping people aren't super attached to
the idea they create in an hour so that
you could have competing hours happening
all over the place and therefore pick
the best one and then work on on that
one next right be like okay what's the
best one that came out of these 20 hours
people did and then let's improve this
one but eventually like a project needs
to actually be made and it's broken up
into tasks that like into project
management things get done things get
paid for and then we have a thing and
then it's like if we fork it it's what
does that mean right does it does it
dissipate it how can we fork it's that
there's diversity without dissipating
the energy without dissipating the data
and there are absolutely ways to do that
if it's not everybody off on their own
right doing their own thing and then
Britt like you can't code reason score
code wiki election and then come
together and mash them up right but you
could as you guys like with that in mind
if you made them and then like in the
future I'm a schlub is that part of what
we're doing right like like bringing in
the later earlier like how can we create
this so they can be brought so or not
right that like they are independent and
then eventually having the conversation
okay how what could we do to bring this
data together what could we do so that
they're feeding off each other their
goals of the co-op council is having
that conversation is a saying should we
ever like connect our systems if so when
and why and if not why yeah so talking
about that because exactly like if we're
keeping them separate because they are
distinct enough that they should ruin
separate in some cases that might make
sense from what I've heard about written
score it definitely sounds like there
could be some overlap and if we're
trying to solve the same problems wiki
election could focus on the other part
of the problem is trying to solve and
just use that to technology if it ends
up being an option yeah yeah I mean that
yeah they can be recombined if while
they're being written they're written
with that in mind like like you said to
blee yeah but I think part of the goal
would be to at most like they work
together
but they're separate enough that if one
Falls the whole thing doesn't have to to
to to fall as well yeah yeah so in in
the community that I'm part of there's
both tasks that absolutely need to get
done sometimes don't get done and we
have to figure out how to get done and
then there's people who do tasks want
like the props and the you know what I
mean for doing the tasks but in no way
needed to get done like it's like we
didn't need another planter and you made
a planter right you didn't need a bench
and you made a bench like it's like
these things aren't and so that's kind
of what like doing your own individual
project could end up being the gold that
was needed but it's more likely gonna be
a bench right like it's most likely
gonna be something that wasn't quite
needed but yeah okay you you did it
great it's here and so how to kind of
together figure out what needs to get
created right and then kind of dole that
out and figure out what you've already
created that is awesome how do we bring
those together and doing both of those
things simultaneously with people still
being able to follow their own
individual and group Drive right like if
I felt stifled between these meetings
that I had to like nothing would be
happening because it would be like I'm
like cool all I have to do is come to
this for an hour and whatever happened
during the week it's like I get to bring
myself to here and I get to do idea cafe
separate and like I get to run with my
ideas and that feels very empowering
instead of like oh wait am i step here
on anyone's toes I have to have a little
bit of trust that if I'm stepping on
someone's toes they're gonna tell me
right and we're gonna figure that out
um versus I don't know versus something
like how that tension right the tension
of like wait I worked on this and now
it's nobody cares about it how many
things did I put out there there's been
crickets that's kind of part of it and
so you actually have to learn very early
on to do as little work on something as
possible we're putting it out there so
you're less attached to it and you're
more willing to have it have it fall
flat or get momentum and have someone
else take off with it right like all
about the same time but that's not easy
to do especially when you you would like
me like to sit in your room and create
something from the ground up and be like
oh this is great I want to play with
this but it doesn't it's not a concrete
thing it's only nebulous unless
other people can come on board and
understand it right and we do that
process together seems a bit like that
sort of I mean it's almost like
pre-project
or you could say it's very early stages
of the meta project where it's actually
verifying the need because you can say
that it has a cool idea and then you
show it to the world and people just
don't care then I mean you can move
forward if you want but you might not
get gain much traction but it's sort of
the opposite we're if also if you show
it to something and they you know people
are super psyched you're like all right
that's a pretty good sign that we should
move forward with this and if it's the
same community that that will also
hopefully helps prevent you know ten
different people from building a slight
variation of the bench unless you know
person one shows up and I said yep
that's a cool bench we want it you know
people two through nine show up they're
like that's the same thing that we
already have and in person ten they're
like that's actually a new bench that is
cool I do want that as well yeah
speaking of onboarding I found the game
beat coffeehouse Trello board and
calendar and they say to get on it you
need to send the DM on Twitter to game B
coffee but game B coffee has closed yeah
direct yes
so there's actually and then when
there's they have a telegram and I went
in there and post it when was that
telegram not half the date as the time
as February 17th it's only been four
days and no useful response from anyone
like how did it get on the Trello board
anyways
that's a little frustrating yes I'm on
the Trello board I think I thought
before I mean like two posts or just to
see it to post or don't vote or to
comment or to have any reaction yeah
it's open it's view it's open to the
public for viewing it's not open for
editing and they have some 38 people on
the board but there's no way to get on
the board there's no way to get onto the
board unless you already have a direct
connection with somebody which I guess I
could find someone on Facebook probably
in direct
message him on there Thank You Christian
on Twitter Bentley and c-h are xn is a
wizard and a son his name and he he is
coffee he's the game B coffee holder
okay since then I think I checked and he
also has his direct messages blocked
unless he's following you
so unless okay cuz I could make him
follow me
there's no way to commune with him
gotcha
yeah that's a problem CX what I'm CH
where are you here CHR xn I'm not even
following him at okay so maybe I didn't
try anyways I think his messages are
just open you can send him one asking
about like what happened to the game bu
Twitter and this is still on the trill
aboard this is your sister contact so
any idea who's currently doing that
cuz I could contact him but then I'm
like introduce you to if you want but
like I don't know how to facilitate the
actual getting you on the trill aboard
losses through you because I don't even
know yeah no it looks like his direct
messages are open I think I actually
can't figure out how to message requests
so what kind of stuff is on that train
of water well first thing an official
calendar so I mean you would think that
the idea cafes would be on there with or
not be on there or at least the game be
the the meetings that you did to Jubilee
that you're doing that you would think
that it I would think that that should
be on there they've only had one meeting
so far
which was the onboard brainstorming
session I think maybe they had to I mean
it's been around for a while I think the
trouble of the game board game be Trello
board has been around for a while I
think a brown the september/october may
be November and it doesn't seem to be
used too much and that's kind of the
problem with it like everything's paid
everything's like if I'm like this is
the issue with everyone trying to solve
their own problem is that none of the
problems actually get solved it's like
I'm an individual and I want to be able
to access Trello without paying $10 like
it's like that you have to pay 6 bucks
per contributor so therefore wordy at 24
with us right like for us to be able to
have a Trello board that's useful it's
like these things need to recreate it so
that like or Google could recreate them
if Google wants to create Trello so that
it's in G Drive I'm good and then we can
like crate from there so I think as
strong as as long as the Trello boards
open I think it's free
there also is and did this isn't just
for game B that this has to be a super
common thing but where people are trying
to solve problems before it's time to
solve them like where it's trying to
make sure that we you know that okay we
can scale up to a thousand people before
we have five and actually can start to
ask people like wait did what features
do we want are people okay with paying
six dollars a month like those sorts of
things and that's like when it came to
working on the like the member system
for the projects and you know and be
able to say what you need help with
maybe people being able to help even
with that up might seems like maybe
we're going overkill first we should
find you know 10 projects that want to
participate in ten people just have you
know solve it in the simplest way like
without software just you know a
facebook chat or something and then once
you get that very small group of people
then start to look at like okay so are
we okay with this system here's five
questions that have about the three or
four routes that we could go what does
everyone think
a good thing to do with the people they
that commented on the like we have 10
projects that people have filled out for
the is to just create a Facebook the
issues we asked them for their emails
and not their facebook Messenger but
Facebook Messenger is probably the
easiest so that it is like hey who's
with your project that's a lot of
dinging though a lot of notifications
but having a space to be able to say
here's my project here's mine
maybe we make a because it's not as long
as we make either I think Jim or Janelle
the one of the amends we can create a
game be project Facebook group that is
one of the meta projects right that is
one of them like I specifically bring
your project here if it's in any way
game be right even a tiny bit and so and
then coordinate that and like we totally
look like a project you know a game be
project board or job board or whatever
you want to call it or yeah it's not
great it's on Facebook it's not super
scalable but you know what let's get to
the point where we're drowning in posts
and you know we're super annoying and
we're missing certain features that were
like alright now we have enough people
that we can actually a ask people some
questions about how to solve it and then
be unday one you know if we make a some
sort of a member portal or or pay for or
whatever on day one we can say great
here's your your users there's often
races you know and we actually got some
stuff to populate it because one of my
things is I'm really hesitant to do
anything that involves another username
and password yeah yes not even last look
well it's more because like there's
another company neat or another group or
anything did someone else also need my
information and like am I going to use
this for more than two days because 90%
of my LastPass stuff I haven't used yeah
I started making a a temp folder where I
throw it in until I know that I use it
be at as it is a pain and so you and I
once it gets to a certain point because
there is the thing we're like solves
that many problems yeah that that's
worth signing up for another user for
but until we're to psych hey we're
trying to solve this thing we're one of
78 different groups indie game beat
space trying to solve it joining another
using a password to see if this works
yeah and so that's where Facebook is the
thing cuz it's where everybody is and
it's just easier to have the different
number ones so I'd say yeah one of us
should create like that seems to be the
Facebook group that we need is the meta
project literally labeled like men a
project a and B or something right like
right yeah like it is if not maybe
matter projects I don't know if that can
really says what it is like the project
of projects like bring your project you
retain ownership but like come and help
each other create Omni win solutions so
like are we thinking that this is just a
a job board love like it's you know hey
I'm doing with the election and I need
help with this in this and Bentley is
doing recent scar he needs help with
this and at each one is there is it more
besides that are we all so well
definitely more besides that I think it
would be even like if cubes fall wants
to come and post everything they've done
with cube spawn they can you don't I
mean like it's a feed of projects so
it's like wiki lecture you can go live
there we can do like or we can piss like
the conversation one is very specific
it's like we're only having conversation
posts so if you post anything that's not
a conversation it's gonna be deleted
even if it's facilitating a conversation
but this is just the place for
conversation and I think there's a
beauty to that but and so maybe it's
just the meta project stuff of like hey
not just what do you think of this but
actually like a call to do a project
raising right you'd like hey I want
people at this time to come and help me
with this this thing okay okay actively
together tech but not called together
tech yet because there's no look no one
knows what that means yeah right right
yeah I think it's very similar I think
though that they're just know yeah like
wiki let there with a wiki election no
game be wiki is potentially trying to do
that but they're like
that's just a page on their board right
that's not actually like they're not
actually trying to do the meta project
that aren't actually trying to say how
do we help each other coordinate our
projects and create it right so that we
Romney winning from day one and had
crazy in a way that's enjoyable like
what does this look like to get to step
on each other's toes but in this space
we're in competition in game a but or
like not in competition who's creating
game B and like what does that look like
and and we have the ten people at least
it like know like hey there's an
invitation to come be part of this and
creating it also so that it's game beat
egg so that because there's gonna be
tons people with projects those are just
the people who saw it right the
algorithm only helps so much and so to
be able to be on the home page like
every project right bring your project
here as long as it's not an MLM game a
like bring it right any app any
community any any like the communities
will be with the communities so that
doesn't necessarily mean unit but some
of those people will be overlaps and it
will be like Colleen has both a Oh
gingka project which is like at the
online farmers market with Harris I
think his name is I had a conversation
with him I should know but yeah and you
don't even like they be in both the
communities and so as part of what they
could do is is that is called so Amana
project or a project right to bring to
that a project is like the people who
have community is what could be
facilitated to help people find and
maintain their communities but that's
not our focus or focuses more on that
like tech projects and things that
aren't like online farmers working as a
tech project they're all basically all
tech projects but that's just because I
don't know if it's not a physical
community it's a tech project I don't
know anything outside that besides cube
spawn I mean cube spawn start I guess
like a physical still tech it's a
physical thing exactly it's like actual
innovation actually yeah I think we're
thinking of like digital versus yes
anything yeah a lot of that will come
out in the wash right like just to get
projects will be like you have a finance
one alright we'll see how it fits cool
like as long as it doesn't and I think
that also helps some of the areas or
like where do we have this conversation
it can start on that group like what are
the things that a project has to have or
can't
an order for it to be a part of this
ecosystem yeah and I honestly feel like
if you're a game B person your projects
games like Nick has a project that he's
he's ready in a financial app and no way
is a game B but he's very game B so I
mean as far as I know right he's writing
it he's like and then I'm gonna use this
money to find other things and so which
I have a couple projects like that to
that especially if they were able to go
under the same umbrella and then we can
figure out okay so with these like
for-profit game B projects how do we
want to handle that was like are there
certain rules how are they different
from the other projects that yeah that's
a super interesting part okay yeah oh I
can create that although I guess we'll
have to decide on the name yeah and so a
game be too bad although not really
it's like Gabey projects it's like
because if the description is like what
it is right it's like bring your project
like for-profit nonprofit they'll start
off with projects okay it's like any
stage any like if you would have
participated in a project crazy and this
is your place to coordinate project
raisins to coordinate whatever help you
need right to be able to have more of
like a calendar I know it's Facebook
still doesn't have a calendar like it
still doesn't have it like this group is
meeting and like you can see when
they're they what whatever if actually
there is a way to live if you use Google
Calendar you can take your Facebook and
see all the events in your Facebook feed
on your Google Calendar but that's all
of mine right so it's all my friends
who've invited me to things I don't even
live in the same city with them no it's
like I'll come to your kid's birthday
and like or is it once I've said yes
those are my even then I don't I'm sure
we I think I think what her no way to me
about it it wasn't just the things I
said yes that would probably be you can
probably link individual calendars
I don't know if they have a different
group for each counter or a different
counter for each group that would be
interesting like I think once we get a
Facebook page up and going a lot of it
is gonna be like popsicle sticks and
glue right so we'll have like a bunch of
sticky you know sticky comments and sigh
panel thing is what we're like hey
here's you know a Google sheet of the
projects and then a column you know for
their for their calendar for their this
for that's just go look at this stuff
you're interested in and then once we
get 25 projects and a hundred people
working on things or whatever that
number ends up being we can start to
look at like alright let's actually do
this well what is that look look look
looks like because right now I think
step one is just get people the irony
also is that like the game be Facebook
group literally has like don't bring
your project here even though people
bring their projects there right it's
like if you think you know how to make
it go make it don't do that here and
it's like but you we want to make things
here like it's like that's important so
having one that is projects so people
don't necessarily need to post in them
in the major one but like people who
want a facility yeah that also gives
them more useful response to people who
are posting project stuff in the game be
like no no no good go go do that here
it's not saying to don't do it saying
great that's cool you have a project
other people who also have projects and
there's a space for it go over here and
there's you know appropriate sticky
comments and pinned things and all that
jazz so we think that game B projects is
that yeah I think for the name of the
thing and then like we need a tagline
for like what actually it is which is
better than but like basically bring
your project and let's co-create Omni
win solutions that help our projects get
off the ground right and deal with
everything that comes up pops the six
igloo guys and this truly it like
there's a decent chance that you know in
a year or two we rename this channel
together tech because it's solving the
like it's serving the exact same purpose
of being that like multi project
facilitator trying to you know find
common things if that it's just together
tech doesn't mean anything yet so we're
gonna say it's game V projects
and try to figure that out answer
questions and if we come up with a
different name in the meantime that
works too
but because part of it was with the
project member portal it was sort of
planning on having together tech just be
one of the projects but now it is sort
of that like the thing the layer on top
of all of it which makes sense of it
being that group a different name cool
and then as people join that are like
not game B but gate B then yeah it
becomes more about do you have a project
and doesn't have a mission it's like
both people with who are game be people
who have projects and people who've
never heard of game B who are just their
projects very day B right like it kind
of brings those like I know like I said
I don't know if Syed is um one if I'm
saying his name right and two if he his
project if he's involved in getting B at
all I don't know how he found us I don't
know who knows but like that's the joy
of this is like you boy like I have a
world-changing project look at it right
and there's no people like that that are
like yeah it's an interesting point if
people don't know about game B if we
call this game B projects is that going
to be confusing is there going to be
limiting do you know it is project you
do we call I don't know like I'm not
sure what a better term might be but do
we want something that's a bit more
descriptive because uh uh as you see
give me projects and you have to go fall
down a rabbit hole for two weeks
figuring out but what is game B I think
that's okay
that's we do want it to be in that game
B space not necessarily in the game B
group space but it is a game B style
project and then if people want to
participate in that they should know
what game B is and what game B is trying
to achieve I guess we can also take a
stab at like a really high level you
know one paragraph like well what is a
game B project what are the thing and
then the community can add on over time
by the product its Omni win its this is
that it's yeah yeah I mean I think we do
need to say I'm new an antivirus we just
might use more intuitive wording than
that right
it helps sense me right like I don't
know if wiki election a recent score at
you driver us or I'm
at the moment but their sense making
which is absolutely needed for her he
wouldn't add yeah and I don't want these
things yeah I actually don't know if it
falls under since making because part of
me makes me wonder whether would they
wouldn't most people use the term sense
making they imply not logical or
rational or post rational or whatever
and reason score is very much a I don't
know whether it's left brain and right
brain but it's it's very much the other
side of intuition it's anti intuition
which is like when you're coming to
something together right because like my
intuition you're into we're trying to
say different things but like why are
they saying that and then I mean
underlining piece and that's where like
with game be as the thing that's very
nebulous and very what is it it's like
doing the personal work doing the
meditation finding your own people
having sovereignty as important but it's
also almost just as important to have a
project you're working on to have
something that is like your purpose and
that is what this is and it's like you
bring your project bring your current
purpose until it either falls away and
you find something better or it becomes
something right like one of the two and
so it's it's like form a group around it
form like we're not there yet but like
that can absolutely coalesce right like
the product like the sense making
project right like bringing wiki
election raises score and kind act
together to be like you know like how do
we how do we help each other in in that
space or people are like wow I really
like recent score and they they come and
help Bentley on that project right for
what what he says he needs and and
figuring out because it's figuring out
how to work on a group in a group right
how do you work in a team to create
something what is the ownership look
like and what is decision and you look
like and so it's like the personal space
thing is like that's what broke up game
be before it was like something more
like we need to do the thing and other
people like no we need to work on our
own sovereignty and figure it out it's
like both both both I do the thing while
you're working on your own sovereignty
and you know people can come and find
project and like you said sorry right
doing the thing is a way to practice
your internal stuff
yeah I mean so I guess we agree that the
priority is practicing on your own and
stuff right is to growing yourself and
just so as long as you keep those
parties it's fine but I don't think you
should say you can't practice while
you're learning anyways yeah yeah
exactly like this is where you can it's
just an easier space for some people who
are like meditation that sounds like
okay it's a practicing group right
practice yeah those people might not be
welcome right they might be to to
conflict Dean and they can't they can't
be part of a team but it's us as a team
figuring that out right be like okay you
can't have too much disruption or
nothing gets done but some disruptions
needed to be able to move things forward
attention is somewhat needed and playing
that out and it's yet because of the
like that sovereign peace right like as
much as I might want to help you guys
move forward with your sovereignty I
can't actually right like I can't
actually force you to meditate or do it
like it's like I can offer what I do and
vice versa we same with the projects
right you can hold on to your project as
tightly and as much as you want but the
more you're willing to let it go and the
more you're willing to have other people
come and work on it and change it the
more it's going to be able to it's gonna
progress in its own way or not some of
them might be needs to be held tightly
by one person right like it's gonna be
different and be able to see that what P
what things work for that are common
across projects and what kind of
projects and the next person learning
from it so they don't have to reinvent
the wheel every time I mean it's cool
this is like something that so it's a
Facebook group we could have done this
weeks ago right but not really because
it's like it needed to have like the
Facebook group kind of breaking up and
people to creating these different these
different facets to be like oh we want
that facet and it's not it like we want
it no one can have it it's like you have
a project come be part of creating the
meta project for projects like be part
of it I'm a little bit afraid of now
having so many different groups that it
will fracture into too many tiny little
bits of pieces but the best like it
seemed maybe people have different con
sepsis patients unwanted work on a thing
oughta move things forward some want a
sort of theory crafts and
intellectualize and planned things and
like there's a bunch of different things
where people like they're itching to do
their own thing and they're
uncomfortable when the group seems to be
headed in a very different direction
just like I'm very like concrete do
things what's our next step like I the
thinking and crafting is cool like it's
in my mind the first step were like you
know in the early phase but then I'm
like alright we answer some questions
well let's go try stuff out yeah and I'm
sure that people who are the opposite
are you know peeling their own issues
with where things are going
absolutely yonas I didn't ask you I'd
mention at the end of the last video are
you coming to Toros idea solution
raising an education um probably not
it's early right six yeah it's nine for
us so I think it's like 3:00 in the
morning or in the morning for you we
decided what is the time we figure this
out all the time but I can't keep it
really super burly yeah way too early
not even stay up late early like very
early and so but I am looking forward to
it cuz it's not even about getting this
solution it's about figuring out the
process to like make that fun and get
the solution and if we come up with a
solution awesome and my rigid
timekeeping we'll see we'll see how well
that goes 15 minutes 15 minutes 30
minutes for the actual solution and it's
like but a Toro and Bentley you're
coming right
I believe Janelle might be coming and I
think Eric as well who was here last
week awesome cool nice week on mm-hmm
so having a discussion like that it'll
be we find it will be hard like because
eric has an idea for education already
like his like any morning so it's partly
that and like I have an idea for
everything but it's like not holding too
tightly to like my idea has to be the
thing you have at the end it's like a
candor needing to talk like it's like 15
minutes and maybe everyone can't share
with the problem with education is it
letting like the the conversation be
alive in and of itself or even if you're
not the one participating it's the thing
that's created by the end it's like oh
that's an actual possible thing that
none of us could have created by
ourselves
it was straight an hour of time also
useful to be explicit in both expecting
that and like acknowledging it like sort
of saying you like your idea and how
that's affecting you I mean not everyone
will be comfortable on that but almost
saying that from the get-go like hey
people are gonna be coming in this with
their own idea people tend to be
defensive of their ideas so whenever
possible let's you know pretty admit or
even at the end saying like oh you know
we came up with this idea I like the
fact you know that this sliver of it
here I I think sort of branched off of
this conversation you know that came
from my ideas so I feel comfortable with
it like my fingerprint is on there
somewhere yeah
like honestly just being part of it you
created it and then even just like I
said later on when there's multiple ones
going on and they're competing with each
other it's like yes you got to
participate in that you still made it
better like yours wasn't chosen this
week but like did you enjoy the thing
right did you enjoy participating and
creating something cuz you also created
something it wasn't created beforehand
and it's seen what all these different
ones create and then how they're
expressed and how yeah but right now
it's just one one conversation one hour
and some people their role might just be
to poke holes and that's still insanely
valuable yeah I like I didn't create it
but I stopped these three things from
happening that would have been bad
taking all the children away and
educating them was not the thing we
wanted to have happen oh that's not God
sound like good idea could see some
historical taking children I can't see
any current you know news events that
might be an alias that would cause
problems yeah her in Canada yeah alright
well we are at the hour mark we have
like 30 seconds left for an hour and we
went we took a little while to go live
said anyone have anything to wrap it up
I'm good
seeing everyone's well - illness Oh see
no no sexy
I think I'm good alright goodbye YouTube
thanks for our second board meeting see
you next week for this and tomorrow for
solutions raising